David's Dust began raking wild
blueberries in Maine in the 1980s.
>> It's pretty hard, especially, you know,
when you don't have many much of your
meniscus left.
>> [laughter]
>> And now I have like two knee braces, a
back brace, two wrist braces.
I'm like half man, half brace.
>> [snorts]
>> Despite the hard [music] work, he
quickly fell in love with the community
of hand harvesters.
He spent the last 38 years taking
pictures of life out here on the
barrens.
>> Yeah, that was my first crew.
>> He keeps many of his prints in his
cabin.
>> He was the top raker on the crew.
Probably '89 or '90 or '91.
>> David's witnessed the shift in who shows
up to harvest from young white punks in
the '90s
>> Was was pretty wild back in the day.
>> To Latino communities from Ecuador and
Guatemala today.
>> And here's Javier and his family.
>> But indigenous pickers have always
returned.
>> Native family, make them all family.
That was my old crew.
And there aren't many bodies of work
that really have this kind of depth.
I mean, it's it's it's [music] kind of
Let's be honest, it's it's sort of
insane. Decades and you know, shot from
the inside and
it is I think a
a good slice of what this world was
like.
You know, that's now vanished.
>> David started coming when most of the
barrens were still being hand harvested.
Thousands of people like him would move
here just to work the wild blueberry
season.
>> Washington County is a very poor county.
So, it was this incredible injection of
you know,
hundreds of millions of dollars
that people were spending here. And
that's all really gone.
Just the whole hand-done culture there
in raking.
The machines have just taken [music]
that world away.
And that's what I love about
the native community. They say they're
really trying to hold on to that.
>> David is one of the few white people on
this raking crew, but he seems to fit
right in.
>> We're playing Manhunt.
>> Uh-oh.
>> It is an extreme round.
>> An extreme round, yeah.
>> Who's what's on our face?
>> Oh, blueberry leaves.
>> Wait, is there a picture of me?
>> These are from the 1990s.
>> 90s and 2000.
>> And then this is this is David.
>> Yeah, that's me.
>> Can you see the resemblance?
>> The resemblance, yeah.
>> Look at him from the top.
>> From the top. Yeah, the top's a goner.
Unfortunately, Mother Nature said,
"You'll be losing that hair."
>> Oh, look what happened to you.
>> Yeah.